Dmitry Bochkov

Junior Front-end Developer

Mobile: +38 066 918 65 45

E-mail: dmitry.bochkov@gmail.com

Skype: dmitry.bochkov

Portfolio: https://DmitryBochkov.github.io **LinkedIn:** https://linkedin.com/in/dmitrybochkov

Objective

To obtain a position of Junior Front-end Developer where I can apply my skills and gain further experience while enhancing the company's productivity and reputation.

Technical Skills

- Proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, SASS/SCSS.
- General knowledge of JavaScript, jQuery, JavaScript templating.
- Understanding of BEM methodology, XML and JSON formats, AJAX techniques, Bootstrap framework.
- Hands-on experience in PSD to HTML conversion, responsive design, crossbrowser layout, pixel perfect implementation of the design in HTML.
- Sound knowledge of graphical editors, SVG and retina graphics.
- Task Runners: Gulp, Grunt.
- Detailed familiarity with GIT version control system and GitHub service.

Language Skills

- English fluent;
- French basic;
- Russian, Ukrainian native.

Soft Skills

During my 10+ years of freelance translation and teaching experience, I've developed strong problem solving, teamwork, and conflict management skills. I have strong analytical skills, ability to quickly learn new technologies, and expertise in planning and organization with attention to details. My background, dedication and adaptability make me a reliable, responsible and effective team player. Besides, I have good organizational abilities and am able to work independently without supervision.

Work Experience

2004—present: Freelance English-Ukrainian/Russian translator.

- Responsibilities: Translation, editing and proofreading; localization of websites; post-DTP proof; personal and business correspondence.
- Areas of expertise: IT, software/hardware, telecommunications.

2001–2014: Teacher of the English language at Teacher Training College.

Education

1998–2003: Luhansk Taras Shevchenko National University; Specialist.

- Department of English Language and Literature,
- Department of Primary Education.

Additional Education

2016, June-October: GoForIT Online Course in Front-end.

2015, August-December: Online Course in Basics of Python Programming.